Stop your squealing, you dunghill rat.
I'm gonna bleed you like a stuck pig.
Not if I stick you first.
Sam!
Oh, Sam, I'm so sorry.
Sorry for everything.
-Let's get you out of here.
-It's too late. It's over.
They've taken it. Sam...
...they took the Ring.
Begging your pardon, but they haven't.
I thought I'd lost you.
So I took it.
Only for safekeeping.
Give it to me.
Give me the Ring, Sam.
Sam.
Give me the Ring.
You must understand.
The Ring is my burden.
It will destroy you, Sam.
Come on, Mr. Frodo.
We best find you some clothes.
You can't go walking through Mordor
in naught but your skin.
We did it, Mr. Frodo.
We made it to Mordor.
There are so many of them.
We'll never get through unseen.
It's him, the Eye.
We have to go in there, Mr. Frodo.
There's nothing for it.
Come on. Let's just make it
down the hill for starters.