Warning? Against what?
We're all afraid, Frodo.
But to let that fear drive us,
to destroy what hope we have...
...don't you see that is madness?
- There is no other way.
I ask only for the strength
to defend my people!
- Lf you would but lend me the Ring.
- No.
- Why do you recoil? I am no thief.
- You are not yourself.
What chance do you think you have?
They will find you.
They will take the Ring.
And you will beg for death
before the end!
You fool!
It is not yours, save by unhappy chance!
It could have been mine.
It should be mine! Give it to me!
- Give it to me!
- No!
- No.
I see your mind.
You will take the Ring to Sauron!
You will betray us!
You'll go to your death,
and the death of us all!
Curse you!
Curse you and all the halflings!
Frodo?
Frodo.