Away with you.
You should not be waking.
Eat earth. Dig deep. Drink water.
Go to sleep.
Away with you.
Come, the forest is waking up.
It isn't safe.
The trees have grown wild
and dangerous.
Anger festers in their hearts.
Black are their thoughts.
Strong is their hate.
They will harm you if they can.
There are too few of us now.
Too few of us Ents left to manage them.
Why are there so few of you
when you have lived so long?
-Are there Ent children?
-Bru-ra-hroom.
There have been no Entings
for a terrible long count of years.
-Why is that?
-We lost the Entwives.
Oh, I'm sorry.
-How did they die?
-Die? No.
We lost them.
And now we cannot find them.
I don't suppose you've seen Entwives
in the Shire?
Can't say that I have.
You, Pip?
What do they look like?
I don't remember now.