Young Master Gandalf.
I'm glad you've come.
Wood and water, stock and stone
I can master.
But there is a wizard to manage here...
... Iocked in his tower.
Show yourself.
Be careful.
Even in defeat, Saruman is dangerous.
Well, let's just have his head
and be done with it.
No.
We need him alive.
We need him to talk.
You have fought many wars
and slain many men, Théoden King...
...and made peace afterwards.
Can we not take counsel together
as we once did, my old friend?
Can we not have peace, you and l?
We shall have peace.
We shall have peace...
...when you answer
for the burning of the Westfold...
...and the children that lie dead there!
We shall have peace
when the lives of the soldiers...
...whose bodies were hewn
even as they lay dead...
...against the gates of the Hornburg,
are avenged!
When you hang from a gibbet
for the sport of your own crows...
...we shall have peace.
Gibbets and crows?
Dotard!
What do you want, Gandalf Greyhame?
Let me guess. The Key of Orthanc.
Or perhaps the Keys of Barad-dûr itself...
...along with the crowns of the seven kings
and the rods of the Five Wizards!
Your treachery has already cost
many lives.
Thousands more are now at risk.
But you could save them, Saruman.
You were deep in the enemy's counsel.
So you have come here for information.
I have some for you.
Something festers
in the heart of Middle-earth.
Something that you have failed to see.
But the Great Eye has seen it.
Even now he presses his advantage.
His attack will come soon.
You're all going to die.
But you know this, don't you, Gandalf?
You cannot think that this Ranger
will ever sit upon the throne of Gondor.
This exile, crept from the shadows,
will never be crowned king.
Gandalf does not hesitate
to sacrifice those closest to him...
...those he professes to love.
Tell me, what words of comfort
did you give the Halfling...
...before you sent him to his doom?
The path that you have set him on
can only lead to death.
I've heard enough!
Shoot him.
Stick an arrow in his gob.
No.
Come down, Saruman...
-...and your life will be spared.
-Save your pity and your mercy.
I have no use for it!
Saruman...
...your staff is broken.
Gríma, you need not follow him.
You were not always as you are now.
You were once a Man of Rohan.
Come down.
A Man of Rohan?
What is the house of Rohan...
... but a thatched barn
where brigands drink in the reek...
...and their brats roll on the floor
with the dogs?
The victory at Helm's Deep does not
belong to you, Théoden Horse-master.
You are a lesser son of greater sires.
Gríma...
...come down.
Be free of him.
-Free? He will never be free.
-No.
Get down, cur!
Saruman!
You were deep in the enemy's counsel.
Tell us what you know!
You withdraw your guard, and I will tell you
where your doom will be decided.
I will not be held prisoner here.