It's a bog. He's led us into a swamp.
A swamp, yes, yes.
Come, master. We will take you
on safe paths through the mist.
Come, Hobbits! Come! We go quickly.
I found it. I did.
The way through the marshes.
Orcs don't use it.
Orcs don't know it.
They go around for miles and miles.
Come quickly.
Soft and quick as shadows we must be.
I hate this place. It's too quiet.
There's been no sight nor sound
of a bird for two days.
No, no birdses to eat.
No crunchable birdses.
We are famished! Yes!
Famished we are, precious!
Here.
What does it eats?
Is it tasty?
It tries to chokes us!
We can't eats Hobbit food!
We must starve!
Well, starve, then. And good riddance!
Oh, cruel Hobbit.
It does not care if we be hungry.
Does not care if we should die.
Not like master.
Master cares.
Master knows.
Yes.
Precious.
Once it takes hold of us. . .
. . .it never lets go.
Don't touch me!
There are dead things!
Dead faces in the water.
All dead. All rotten.
Elves and Men and Orcses.
A great battle long ago.
Dead Marshes.
Yes. Yes, that is their name.
This way.
Don't follow the lights.
Careful now! Or Hobbits go down
to join the dead ones. . .
. . .and light little candles
of their own.
Frodo!
-Gollum?
-Don't follow the lights.
-Gollum!
-Mr. Frodo!
Are you all right?