I suppose you think
that was terribly clever.
Come on, Gandalf.
Did you see their faces?
There are many magic rings in this world,
and none of them should be used lightly.
It was just a bit of fun.
Oh, you're probably right, as usual.
- You will keep an eye on Frodo, won't you?
- Two eyes.
As often as I can spare them.
- I'm leaving everything to him.
- What about this ring of yours?
- Is that staying too?
- Yes, yes.
It's in an envelope over there
on the mantelpiece.
No. Wait, it's...
...here in my pocket.
Isn't that...? Isn't that odd, now?
Yet, after all, why not?
- Why shouldn't I keep it?
- I think you should leave the ring behind.
Is that so hard?
Well, no.
And yes.
Now it comes to it,
I don't feel like parting with it.
It's mine. I found it! It came to me!
- There's no need to get angry.
- Well, if I'm angry, it's your fault!
It's mine.
My own.
- My precious.
- Precious?
It's been called that before,
but not by you.
What business is it of yours
what I do with my own things?
I think you've had that ring
quite long enough.
- You want it for yourself!
- Bilbo Baggins!
Do not take me for some conjurer
of cheap tricks.
I am not trying to rob you.
I'm trying to help you.