He's not welcome.
Why should I welcome you. . .
. . .Gandalf Stormcrow?
A just question, my liege.
Late is the hour. . .
. . .in which this conjurer
chooses to appear.
Láthspell I name him.
I'll news is an I'll guest.
Be silent. Keep your forked tongue
behind your teeth.
I have not passed
through fire and death. . .
. . .to bandy crooked words
with a witless worm.
His staff.
I told you to take the wizard's staff.
Théoden. . .
. . .son of Théngel. . .
. . .too long have you sat
in the Shadows.
I would stay still if I were you.
Hearken to me!
I release you. . .
. . .from the spell.
You have no power here. . .
. . .Gandalf the Grey.
I will draw you, Saruman,
as poison is drawn from a wound.
Wait.
If I go, Théoden dies.
You did not kill me. . .
. . .you will not kill him.
Rohan is mine.
Be gone.