My master, Sauron the Great,
bids thee welcome.
Is there any in this rout
with authority to treat with me?
We do not come to treat with Sauron...
...faithless and accursed.
Tell your master this:
The armies of Mordor must disband.
He is to depart these lands,
never to return.
Old Greybeard.
I have a token I was bidden
to show thee.
Frodo.
-Silence.
-No!
Silence!
The Halfling was dear to thee, I see.
Know that he suffered greatly
at the hands of his host.
Who would've thought one so small
could endure so much pain?
And he did, Gandalf.
He did.
And who is this?
Isildur's heir?
It takes more to make a king
than a broken Elvish blade.
I guess that concludes negotiations.
I do not believe it.
I will not.
Pull back.
Pull back!
It's gone, Mr. Frodo.
The light's passed on,
away towards the north.
Something's drawn its gaze.
Hold your ground! Hold your ground.
Sons of Gondor, of Rohan, my brothers!
I see in your eyes...
...the same fear that would take
the heart of me.
A day may come
when the courage of Men fails...
...when we forsake our friends
and break all bonds of fellowship.
But it is not this day.
An hour of wolves
and shattered shields...
...when the age of Men
comes crashing down.
But it is not this day.
This day we fight!
By all that you hold dear
on this good earth...
... I bid you stand, Men of the West!